Leo Przybylski | Resumé

2450 N. Palo Hacha – Tucson, AZ – United States № 5204401252 • ☑ r351574nc3 at gmail.com

† https://www.github.com/r351574nc3/
https://www.linkedin.com/in/r351574nc3/

Profile

A multitool of software engineering. I started software engineering over 25 years ago on mainframe systems. Since then, I have developed automation, user interfaces, and backends for video games, code generation algorithms, natural language processing, financials, research administration, student system administration, CMS, digital libraries, scientific programming, machine learning systems, embedded software, software deployment, storage systems, SaaS administration, and robotics.

I work primarily in software engineering and automation of cloud infrastructure and orchestration; however, I also enjoy DevOps and Configuration Management. I have used the GNU/Linux operating system for over 20 years. I have run it as my primary desktop operating system for over 15, and have administered it for over 15 years as well. I have built and managed firewalls with Linux as well as installed it on several devices that are not servers or desktops. I have also built Linux-based network appliances (not just firewalls). I can build both RPMs, Debian, and emerge packages.

Specialties: Quality Assurance, Configuration Management, Creative Problem Solving, Go, java, ruby, perl, python, c/c++, Jenkins, drone, maven, junit, testing, mockito, cucumber, docker, puppet, opsworks, aws, spring, sequelize, GWT, arduino, ReST, SOAP, SOA, ORM, Liquibase, UML, and Technical Writing.

Programming Lanuages: Node.js, Javascript, Go, Ruby, Java, Scala, Scheme, Clojure, Python, Perl, Sed, Awk, Lisp, C/C+++, and Bash

Cloud Infrastructure: Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, Openstack **Operating Systems:** Linux, AIX, VAX/Vms, FreeBSD, Solaris, and Mac OS X

Frameworks: Play Framework, Akka, backbone.js, AngularJS, VueJS, GWT, Ruby on Rails,

SpringBoot, Grails, and DJango

Messaging: Kafka, Storm, RabbitMQ

Database platforms: DynamoDB, MongoDB, Cassandra, CouchDB, Redis, Oracle, and PostgreSQL

Build Tools: drone, Gitlab CI, SBT, Bazel, maven, jenkins, and gradle

Key Competencies

16 years experience including n-tier enterprise application development with Java, software documentation with UML, and working with unified/agile processes.

- Developed software using Ruby, Python, Groovy, and Perl scripting languages.
- Strong agile/kanban/iconix development process experience.
- Generated source code of XML, SQL, and interpreted scripting languages.
- Developed software using SOA and template-driven UI with Oracle and MySQL.
- o Strong experience with Struts, Spring MVC, RoR, Django, Play Framework, and Grails.

- Experience with Rich and Simple domain models with OR/M.
- NOSQL database experience with databases like Berkeley DB, BigTable, Redis, and CouchDB.
- Enthusiasm and motivation to work with new technologies.
- Experienced with Web Components and Polymer/Xtags.
- Proven experience with javascript web frameworks like EmberJS and AngularJS.
- Proven experience in rich user interfaces with javascript libraries ¡Query, Dojo, prototype, and scriptaculous.
- Experience developing Scala on Open Source Software (OSS) projects built on the Play Framework. (Approximately 5 years on 3 projects)
- Experience with Scala for Android.
- Aware of tools useful in varying applications, and actively searches for better solutions to improve work output and productivity.
- Proven experience in rich user interfaces with AJAX.
- Capable of writing/maintaining technical documentation and specifications with LaTeX, UML/ER diagrams, flowcharts, Atlassian Confluence or Microsoft Word.
- Strong familiarity with SCM tools RPM, Jenkins, Ant, Ivy, Maven 3, SVN and Git.
- Strong familiarity with metadata standards and ontologies including RDF, Dublin Core, FOAF, Microformats, OWL, DAML, and OAI.
- Some experience in VB 5.0 from 1997 1998.

Experience

Rackspace San Antonio, TX

Site Reliability Engineer

2018-Current

- Migrating legacy python 2 application to python 3 (flask) micro-services.
- Mission critical application development and maintenance.
- Developing tools for infrastructure as a service deployment and maintenance.
- Automated deployments to Openshift platform.
- Developed Knative over Openshift proof-of-concept.

Rackspace San Antonio, TX 2016-2018

Platform Engineer

- o Developed generators with yeoman for application pipelines designed around kubernetes, docker, and jenkins.
- Developed extensions to kubernetes (custom resources and controllers) and helm in golang
- Developed an event-driven service graph and service discovery architecture that leverages kubernetes
- Developed Sonatype Nexus extension that provides insight into charts deployed to nexus and integration with helm
- Developed event-driven deployment orchestration third-party-resource for kubernetes
- Implemented/Designed reactive Command Request/Query Separation pattern using kafka for event sourcing
- Unit testing generators with mocha and chai as promised.
- o Developed proprietary OAuth2 plugin for Kibana using Bell for OAuth2 using NodeJs.
- Developed custom Elastic X-pack realm for proprietary identity management and access control integration.

Raytheon Missile Systems

Tucson, AZ

Software Engineer- Hitachi Consulting

2015–2016

- Added Access Control List features to an application built with KnockoutJS, Spring, D3JS, Oracle, and EclipseLink technologies
- Developed wizard control elements for KnockoutJS applications
- Created an interim Maven repository within SVN until Nexus OSS repository and JFrog Artifactory repository could be evaluated for use.
- o Developed Jenkins Project plugin for proprietary software development framework project creation.
- Developed Yeoman scaffolds for Maven archetypes, Gradle project templates, Docker templates, and NodeJS application.
- Developed Maven archetypes for proprietary software development framework projects.
- Restructured an entire project for Maven Multi-Module applications with Maven Overlays, Spring Boot, and SVN Externals.
- Refactored a large project with static method singleton applications into dependency injected singletons for event and message-driven architecture with Spring Boot, Kafka, and Storm.
- Refactored Storm Bolts to run as Spring Boot contexts.
- o Documented architecture, refactoring changes, howto guides, and developer guides with Docbook.
- Created UML class/relationship and sequence diagrams for architecture designs of refactorings.
- Created project standards for Jenkins projects including Jacoco configuration, Maven execution configuration, and build pipelines.
- Provided documentation and training to developers on the Maven Build Lifecycle, Maven Modules, Maven encryption, and Maven releases.

American ExpressPhoenix, AZSoftware EngineerApril 2015–May 2015

- Machine Learning development.
- Big Data ETL development.
- Developed a Maven archetype for automatically building Maven modules from Talend ETL jobs.
- Developed a process for automating unit testing of Talend ETL jobs with JUnit, Jenkins CI, Mockito, and Cobertura code coverage.
- Developed a process for automating environment deployments of Talend ETL jobs from a Nexus repository using Maven, Jenkins CI, and capistrano.
- Developed a POC for porting a J2EE application built with Spring, EJB, Struts, and DB2 to AngularJS, NodeJS, D3.js, and MongoDB with Siteminder SSO integration.
- Developed a POC for replacing ETL using CSV flat files with an HBase (Google Big Table) solution including performance evaluation of transformation speed and resource consumption.
- Developed a testable change management refinement for Talend ETL jobs using RPM and Vagrant.
- Streamlined execution and configuration management of Talend ETL jobs including a refinement allowing jobs written in different versions of Talend Open Studio to execute together.
- Documented development and testing processes using Docbook and Microsoft Sharepoint.

rSmart Scottsdale, AZ
SaaS Develooper May 2014–October 2014

- Tools development and features for rSmart Cloud Express platform. These are often tools written in Java or Ruby that work with AWS, Puppet, Hiera, Maven, Jenkins, Tomcat, and MySQL.
- Technical advice and guidance directly to the Vice President of Product Development for rSmart Cloud Express on systems and software architecture.
- Work to improve the open source software our product is based on, Kuali Coeus, by adding features and contributing back fixes.
- Development of data migration scripts and tools by developing custom Maven plugins. I also develop custom data migration tools using ReST, Ruby, Spring Framework, and Jersey.
- To improve continuous delivery and adapt software to be more favorable to multitenant applications, I ported a metadata architecture to NoSQL Redis datastore.
- Development of Maven archetypes for KFS, Kuali Coeus, and Kuali Rice platforms to simplify institutions starting new projects.
- Development of integration for Gerrit Code review into Kuali Enterprise Workflow in order to manage real-time modifications to a live application with a workflow.
- o Software training for Kuali Rice and KRAD.
- Preparation of online training tools using Google coursebuilder.

Education

Pima County Community College
AGECS
Tucson, AZ
1994–1999
University of Arizona
Tucson, AZ
Incomplete, Linguistics/Computer Science
2008–Present

References

Available upon request